Gabriel Lombardi

Summary

Support Engineer with a background in Data Analytics and a degree in engineering. Bringing experience in project development, process optimization, and automation using programming languages, focusing on delivering efficient and scalable solutions. Currently, I apply my technical expertise to support IT operations, drive process improvements, and solve complex challenges, bridging engineering and technology to enhance business outcomes.

Experience

Support Engineer – December 2024 to the present **Atlassian**, Florianópolis (WFH).

- IT Service Management.
- Customer Support Services.
- Improving knowledge bases.

Commercial Analyst – March 2024 to December 2024 **Ultragaz**, Florianópolis.

- Business Intelligence.
- Dashboard maintenance.
- Creating and updating indicators.
- Exploring new market and potential clients.

Data Analyst – May 2023 to February 2024

Figueirense FC, Florianópolis.

- Performance analysis.
- Data extraction and database maintenance.
- Participating in report elaboration and presentation.
- Overseeing athlete development.

Planning and control consultant – February 2020 to January 2023

MRV engineering, Porto Alegre and Florianópolis.

- Costs management and service planning to improve strategy and process mapping.
- Developing projects to ensure the process flow.
- Ensuring conformity in building plans.
- Cooperating in effective, safe and sustainable construction sites.

Safety engineering intern – February 2020 to March 2020 **NR Medical and Engineering**, Curitiba

Civil engineering intern – March 2017 to December 2017 **Alves, Fardin Engineering**, Porto Alegre

Engineering intern – January 2017 to March 2017 **Hotel Consulte**, Porto Alegre

Education

Data Science and big data analytics: IT Post graduation - 2024

Universidade Estácio de Sá (UNESA).

Bachelor of Engineering: Civil Engineering - 2019 Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS), RS

Post-graduation: Safety engineering – incomplete

Federal University of Technology - PR

Additional activities

 Software experience: Excel, Visual Basic, Power BI, Word, PowerPoint, Project, Jira, JSM, Revit, AutoCAD 2D & 3D, Sony Vegas, SAP ECC;

Developer Certifications: Python, Django, Power BI – Udemy – 2023.
 Angular Framework – DIO – 2023.
 Software development good practices – MOOC Unicamp – 2023;

Javascript – Trybe – 2023.
AWS – DIO – 2023.
AWS – DIO – 2023.

- Product management: Cubos Academy 2023
- Certifications: Six-sigma Yellow belt certification 2015, Open dojo program, development of human competencies, strategic and entrepreneurship skills - Universidade da Experiência Uexp – Curitiba - 2016;
- Volunteering activities: Construction working in emergency houses Teto Paraná 2016;
- Internacional experience: CISV camps from 2010 through 2013 and AFS exchange program in Italy
 2012;
- Scientific initiation: Institute of hydraulic research UFRGS 2015. Technological Innovation Fair FINOVA UFRGS 2015.
- Published Articles: ANALYSIS OF THE DISCHARGE COEFFICIENT BEHAVIOR IN SMALL CONDUIT
 SYSTEMS AN EXPERIMENTAL STUDY XXI Brazilian symposium of water resources. Energy and water efficiency in sanitation Academic journal: Revista da Extensão UFRGS PROREXT.

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Problem solving
- Organization
- Planning and control
- Process mapping
- Cooperation

Languages

- Portuguese fluent
- English fluent
- Italian advanced
- Japanese beginner